We wasted four years squabbling over
some peninsula's sovereignty,
and in the end,
our two main Battle Titans
were nearly shredded
by the guns of the enemy fleet.
"The weapons of mankind
have at last grown
strong enough to
sunder Marley's armor."
Headlines the world over
hold up this battle
as proof of our weakness.
So we can't truly call it
a victory for our nation,
now can we?
Well? Speak.
What do you make of this, Magath?
Frankly, General,
we knew this day would come, and it has.
The power of the Titans
has been surpassed.
Our time's run out.
We've been content to rely
on the power of the Titans
as we expand our colonial holdings.
Meanwhile, countries that
lacked Titans to rely on
developed weapons to oppose them.
And now, our complacency
is about to bite us in the ass.
When it comes to ground engagements,
our Titan forces should
reign supreme for a while yet.
That said, if aircraft
keep advancing at this rate,
they will soon make bombs
rain from the sky.
And when that time comes,
Titans, the devils of the earth,
will only be able to look up and watch.
We don't have any Titans
with wings, do we?
Please, General.
What I'm saying is that we
can no longer depend on...
The Titans, yes.
As a result, our global military
dominance will soon falter.
Or, we've lost our grip on it already.
It's funny. We've gone
from the nation of heroes
who crushed the Eldian Devils,
to whatever the hell we are now.
Begging your pardon, General.
If you'd forgive my boldness.
I have some thoughts on this.
Ah, Zeke the boy wonder.
Go right ahead.
It's time we resumed
the Paradis Operation,
so that we can take control
of the Founding Titan.
It's just as Commander Magath was saying.
We must adapt.
Marley will need to modernize
her military, starting now.
However, the world will not stand by
and wait for her to do it.
Reforming the army will take time.
And the best way to buy that
time is by giving the newspapers
of the world a new headline to publish.
Something like this:
"Marley defeats the devils of Paradis
and seizes the power
of all nine Titans."
Hmm.
Forgive the reminder, but won't
your term be up in a year?
Yes. And I'm quite anxious
about whether or not
Colt can inherit the full
power of the Beast Titan.
Ah, I get it.
You wish to use your last
year to redeem yourself.
You don't want to die with
unfinished business, is that it?
You understand me completely.
My father, Grisha Jeagar,
set something great and terrible
in motion on that island.
And as his former son,
I would like to be the end of it.
Sorry for insulting your competence
to further my agenda, Colt.
No, I'm glad you did.
Seeing all those officers listening
to an Eldian was amazing.
And you're right.
There hasn't been a Beast
like you in history.
Your Beast is like
a second Founding Titan.
What makes you so special, Zeke?
It's not like you have
royal blood in your veins.
Who can say?
Chances are, I'll be dead
before we can figure it out.
Oh, but since you'll
inherit the Beast from me,
you'll see my memories,
and learn my secret.
Your secret? About what?
The way I wipe my ass.
It's real special.
Hope you don't tell anyone.
Too late. I want a full report.
Commander!
You tell me everything,
down to the number of hairs on your ass.
Do you think Eldians deserve privacy?
Certainly not, sir.
So you believe you can
conquer Paradis in a year?
All that I can say for a fact
is that I only have
a year left to try, sir.
In the past three years,
that island has swallowed up
every survey ship we've
sent to it: No survivors.
Tell me. What do you
make of that, Zeke?
Considering the fact that none
of those 32 ships have returned,
I think it's clear that
we're dealing with
more than one Titan.
My best guess is that Eren coordinated
with the Colossal or Female.
Sinking our ships while
blocking their escape.
A fair assessment.
Our ships won't be able
to land on the island
without heavy support.
Right. And we'd
do well to remember.
It isn't just their Titans
that pose a threat.
Wait...!
Sounded like you were
having an extra sweet dream,
so I thought I'd let you enjoy it.
You saved my life at Fort Slava.
Thanks, Galliard. I owe you.
Don't want your thanks.
If I had inherited the
Armored Titan nine years ago,
then none of this would've happened.
My brother would still be alive,
'cause he wouldn't have gotten
eaten trying to protect you.
So you've seen Marcel's memories?
I haven't, but I learned what I needed to
from my predecessor, Ymir.
An ironically grand name
for such a pitiful woman.
She basically volunteered
to give my brother's
jaws back. Right?
Yeah. She did.
What did you even do
on that island anyway?
Stumble around finding
people to save you?
Yeah.
I saw you through her memories.
You acted like you were
the tough, reliable type.
Not at all like yourself.
Did you think you could
fill my brother's shoes?
Pock. We shouldn't
pick on people
who've been hit by artillery.
That's not my name,
Pieck. Stop it.
How are you?
It's been about two months since
the last time I was human.
Kinda forgot how the
whole bipedal thing works.
By the way, Reiner.
You oughta visit Gabi and the others.
They're worried about you.
Right, will do.
I'm pooped.
Feels like I haven't seen you in forever.
Really? Even though we're
always fighting side by side?
Well, we shouldn't have to for a while.
We can hope.
This way.
Sure.
Hey, uh. If Titans
become obsolete soon,
what will that mean for us?
If Eldians lose their use, then...
I was talking to my neighbor...
Mr. Braun will be fine.
Yeah, I know.
Look.
They're enemy soldiers.
Probably survivors of
the Pure Titan attack.
And once they get
back home, they'll become
living proof of how
inhumane Titan warfare is.
Every time this happens,
it makes us Eldians
look more like monsters!
"Good people of the world!
Let us wipe out
the Subjects of Ymir!"
Shit! Shit! Shit!
Udo, stop.
Don't hit town property.
Reiner! So.
You're good to walk again?
Yeah. What about
all of you? Gabi?
- -Udo.
- -I guess.
Zofia.
I'm all right.
- -Falco.
- -Hello.
Hey! Did you hear?
They're gonna take us
all back to Liberio soon!
Come on, we can explore town until then.
Wait...
We never get chances like this...
Mr. Braun's healing, he prob'ly
needs to go back to bed soon.
I'm all right. Don't worry.
Maybe you should go back to bed.
No, I'm coming with you guys.
Hey, wait! Commander Magath said
that place is only for lonely adults.
Are you sure? 'Cause I
just saw him go in.
Don't worry so much.
Wait!
You kids are too young to go in there.
Aww.
Who else saw it?
How many of you witnessed the courage
of our Eldian goddess here?
She took on an armored train.
And she did it alone,
in the place of 800 Eldian soldiers!
How drunk are you?
Your breath's awful.
C'mon, ya big dummy,
tell 'em why ya did it!
Comrades! Do you have
any idea why this idiot
risked her life to destroy that train?
All right, I'll say it then!
She did it for all of you!
To save your sorry Eldian asses
from the enemy's bullets!
I'll go shut 'em up.
Let's look the other way.
Give 'em this one night.
Gabi! Gabi! Gabi!
I'm the best!
I'm the best! I'm the best!
Not the first time
I've seen her up there.
I really wish they'd stop
letting my brother drink.
And Gabi gets carried away too easily.
That said, if she keeps
on performing at the level
she has been, she'll get the Armor.
Yeah. The girl who looks
up to you more than anyone
will inherit your Titan
and will die at age 27.
And that's if an artillery shell doesn't
take her down first.
Are you really okay with that?
Did you just say what I think you did?
How dare you claim that
inheriting one of the Nine
is less than an honor.
If I choose to report this,
it'll be you and your family dropped out
of an airship as Titans next.
Wait. Please don't do that.
I'm so sorry: Allow me
to correct myself.
I, Warrior Candidate Falco Grice,
wish to atone for my ancestor's crimes
and for my wicked blood.
Towards that end,
I pledge my life to Marley.
And what are your thoughts on the honor
of inheriting one of the Nine,
Warrior Candidate?
Inheriting one of the Nine
makes you an Honorary Marleyan.
Nothing would make me prouder
than to be given such a chance
to display my loyalty to the motherland.
Then you must want to inherit the Armor.
I don't just want to inherit
the Armor. I have to.
That's right.
Surpass Gabi to protect her.
Spare her from the dark future we face.
Woohoo! We're finally back!
I swear, the air tastes
different here in Liberio!
Guess who's home!
Hey. Please, I asked
you not to yell.
Yeah, well I asked you not to
drink so much, lightweight.
I don't understand
who would give him wine
in the first place.
I thought he looked like
he could use a nightcap.
Come on, Colt.
How could you spew Pieck's kindness
all over the train like that?
I suppose we should've
shut them up after all.
Our comrades were
chanting your name all night.
Colt put them up to it.
No worries. You deserved
a healthy dose of praise.
What you did really was impressive.
Thanks a lot, Pieck!
Vice Chief Braun.
Is he thinking the same thing as me?
Does he want Eldians
to be free from war, too?
If so, can I trust him?
All right. Take it easy,
enjoy your break!
Not me! I'll get back
to training tomorrow!
What, are you trying to
boost your grades?
Ugh, will ya gimme a break?
No! That's not
what this is about!
Hey, you two.
Try not to push yourselves too hard.
Hey, Dad.
Ah, Zeke.
Grandpa! Grandma!
It's so good to see you.
We're so very proud of
all your achievements.
I'm not done. Not yet.
Colt! Falco!
Colt! You look so pale!
There they are! Mom! Dad!
Gabi!
Reiner.
You must be exhausted.
Let's get you home so you can rest.
Hey, Mom. A little
rest sounds good.
Uh. I'll meet you all in a bit.
Ugh. For crying out loud!
Don't you know how to stand anymore?
Mr. Koslow. What's wrong
with these soldiers?
Ugh. Stay outta
the way, you nosy brat.
This is a sorry bunch of
Eldians with mental trauma.
It happens to our guys, too?
It's from all that time
digging on the front lines,
surrounded by bombs and bullets.
In their heads, these guys
are still in the trenches.
Kaboom!
Wow. Guess their killer
instincts kicked in.
Hey, it's all right.
You're not in danger.
Your armband's on the wrong side.
It's okay, sir.
I'm sure that you'll get better.
It's over now.
You don't have to fight anymore.
Kaboom!
The grenades landed
exactly where I'd aimed them
and blew the train right off its tracks!
I'd actually pulled it off!
But as I was running
back to the trenches,
the enemy shot a machine gun at me,
and just as I was about to eat lead, uh...
Mr. Galliard jumped in
out of nowhere
and protected me with his Jaw Titan!
That's amazing, Gabi!
It sounds like a whole
bunch of our soldiers
owe their lives to your bravery!
Our little girl has grown
into an Eldian hero!
We couldn't be prouder of you, dear.
Reiner.
Do you think Gabi will
become a Warrior like you?
Yeah. After what she
pulled off at Fort Slava,
she's all-but guaranteed
to inherit my Armor.
That's wonderful to hear.
To think that our family will be
blessed with two Warriors.
It's such a rare honor.
I just hope you'll find
a way to rid the world
of those island devils.
After that, our people will
be able to live good lives.
Say, Reiner. Not to pry, but...
I hear you barely escaped from
those devils with your life.
Leave Reiner alone, Dad.
His time on that island isn't
some light-hearted war story.
Those devils put him through hell.
So even if it wasn't classified,
there's no way that it's something
he would wanna talk about.
You're right. Sorry,
nephew. Forgive me.
No. I can tell you some things.
As you know,
I infiltrated their military.
As expected, they acted like devils.
Each of them was savage and cruel.
During our induction, one devil
started eating a potato.
When the instructor yelled
at her, she told him,
without hesitation, that she
stole it 'cause it looked good.
She knew she's crossed a line,
so she bribed the instructor
by offering him half the potato.
However, the half she offered him
was visibly smaller than her half.
They don't even know what
compromise means there.
Each of them was more
hopeless than the last.
There was one guy so stupid he'd forget
why he'd gone into the bathroom.
An insincere jerk who only
ever thought about himself.
A soft-hearted oaf who
only ever thought of others.
A brave but single-minded fool,
and a bunch of chumps
who followed his lead.
Alongside all those different people,
stood me and my comrades.
The time that we spent
there was truly hell.
I said way too much. Forget it.
What do you mean by "different people"?
They're bad people, right?
Of course they are,
Gabi. They're all devils.
And they're holding this
whole world by the throat.
They could unleash their army
of huge Titans at any moment
and crush us all beneath their feet.
They aren't anything like you and me.
We're good Eldians.
And we have to stop them.
We have to punish the wicked
Eldians who abandoned us.
Who fled and built themselves a paradise
on top of a mountain of corpses.
Everything okay, Gabi?
You seem upset.
You do know that Aunt Karina's
worried about you, right?
She says that you changed on the island.
That her kid is gone.
Well. I left as
a 12-year-old boy,
and came back a grown man,
so she's not exactly wrong.
It feels like
you're lying. So...
Lying? Why would I bother?
Honestly, I have no idea.
But I feel like Aunt
Karina's worked it out.
I heard it was a soldier.
That's awful.
Hey, good morning.
Looks like all of us are here now.
This is a rare occasion.
Why are we all meeting
in your office, Zeke?
And where's the brass?
They're not here in this room.
Can't we all just meet for some tea?
Sure...
Now then. The battle of
Fort Slava made it clear
that conventional weapons
are advancing fast.
They'll soon be stronger than Titans.
That's bad news on two fronts.
We'll lose our tactical value
as Marley loses her strength.
This threatens the whole Eldian race.
And there is but one solution.
Marley must seize the
Founding Titan's power
as well as the resources of Paradis.
Before that, the world
must be reminded of
the terrible threat
that island poses to us all.
And every good story needs a narrator.
The Tybur family will provide one for us.
They're the keepers of
the War Hammer, is that right?
Yeah, but the Tybur's
have never once used
the War Hammer Titan
against an enemy state.
They're known as the family that
drove off King Fritz
in the Great Titan War.
They aren't hated like most Eldians.
If we speak through the Tyburs,
the world will hear us out.
Astute as ever, Pieck!
You're exactly right!
But the Tyburs have been living lives
of luxury and freedom.
They've never fought for
their country or their people.
Why should they get to play hero now?
I know how you feel, but the Tyburs are
just as concerned about Marley as we are.
Maybe. But they're...
If it saves our motherland, Marley,
that's enough for me.
Our duty as Warriors
is to support the Tyburs,
and to serve as scaffolding
as a new Marley is built.
Well said.
Very soon, a festival will
take place here in Liberio.
You don't say.
Foreign dignitaries
and VIPs will be invited
to hear this announcement
from the Tyburs:
We will conquer Paradis
Island within the next year.
The fates of the Eldian people
and of Marley rest on this plan.
We cannot let it fail.
For the future of our motherland Marley,
we must join our hearts and minds as one.
All right, then.
Galliard has a complaint or two,
but he always follows orders in the end.
If this is all they're saying
in private, I'm not concerned.
I just wish Zeke hadn't
thrown that comment in.
"Not here in this room," huh.
Will I have to go
back... to that damn island?
Honorary Marleyan.
Esteemed Warrior.
What he wanted to be.
What he never could be.
Did he choose the right path?
Did he have a choice?
Next episode:
"The Door of Hope."